Nicolas Mitrano

70 Forest Hills Way, Cedar Grove, NJ 07009 | Cell (973) 735-7140 | Email: ncmitran@syr.edu | nicom917@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Pursuing a major in Information Management and Technology at the iSchool of Syracuse University. Effectively mastered time-management in the workplace, and have before demonstrated courtesy and patience when dealing with clients. Versed in a professional level of customer service, which has reinforced my interpersonal and problem resolution skills in time sensitive situations. Pursuing an internship in an IT oriented discipline to further enrich my already completed coursework with real workplace experiences

EDUCATION

Syracuse University, Syracuse, New York

Pursuing a degree in Information Management & Technology, with a minor in Project Management, Information Security Management, and Digital Retail Strategies Aug. 2019 - Jun. 2023

Information Technology Coursework

- Effectively managed multiple responsibilities and demands using problem solving and time management skills
- Employed a wide variety of team management and interpersonal skills to navigate through complex issues in a group environment
- Demonstrated a willingness to adapt, commit, and overcome to foreign challenges in unfamiliar environments

Experience

IT Consultant - Head Leadership Position, Whitman School of Management. Syracuse, NY

Sep. 2021 - Current

- Manage and mentor a team of nine students by providing them experiential insights and tools to optimize their performance and morale
- Demonstrated on-the-spot, tailored, applicable problem solving skills regarding a variety of different customer requests and issues
- Maintained, managed, and provided support for a diverse array of client tickets/requests and executed custom solutions in real time
- Worked closely alongside a team of IT professionals to measure, plan, and assess different technical challenges and provide relevant solutions in a timely manner

Lead Website Developer, Pan International Conference Translation Services. Montclair, NJ

Jun. 2018 - Sep. 2018

- Created and implemented mock wireframe designs according to client's requests
- Designed, planned, executed, and finalized a functional website from the ground up to act as the face of the company
- Created responsive, intuitive, and accessible user interfaces to allow clients to access the sites from any device
- Took creative initiative and design oriented liberties to build a logically cohesive website and accompanying format

Customer Service Representative, Domino's. Cedar Grove, NJ

Jan. 2017 - Jan. 2018

- Provide great communication and customer service to clients in person and over the phone to ameliorate a plethora of unique concerns
- Managed and communicated effectively with other team members in a fast paced kitchen environment that averages 80 orders an hour
- Demonstrate a high-level of time management under pressure while routinely switching to different tasks

Banquet Server, The Grove. Cedar Grove, NJ

Jun. 2018 - Sep. 2018

- Successfully plan, maintain, and deconstruct up to three different events over the course of 11-19 hour shifts for up to 400-500 guests
- Practiced a professional standard of patience, dedication, and overall professionalism when catering to guests specific wants and needs

VOLUNTEER WORK / PERSONAL ENDEAVORS

Camp Counselor, Camp New Day. Stroudsburg, PA

Aug. 2018 – Sep. 2019

- Responsible for leading and providing support to a variety of different developmentally disabled adults throughout their day
- · Guided campers by aiding with meals, getting dressed, time management, hygiene, activities, and any other challenges
- Facilitated problem resolution techniques with campers who were distressed or in conflict with other individuals

Desktop Solutions Work / Experience, Self-Employed, Cedar Grove, NJ

Jul. 2015 - Jul. 2019

• Designed, constructed, and supported tailored desktop solutions for clients based on a wide array of personal wants and needs

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE/SKILLS

- Salesforce
- Microsoft Project
- Microsoft Azure
- Tableau
- Microsoft SQL
- T-SQL & Relational Databases
- C++

- Python
- Amazon Web Services
- Google Office Suite
- Google Cloud Services
- Microsoft Office 365 Suite (Word, Excel, PP, etc)
- Teamviewer, Slack, Zoom, Skype, Teams
- HTML
- SQL
- Windows, Linux, Mac
- Exodus, metamask, binance, kucoin,gemini, crypto ecosystem